Sufyan Saleem

Address: Phase 6, Sector F8, Street 4, House 425, Hayatabad, Peshawar

Website: https://sufyansaleem.netlify.app/
Email: sufyansalim94@gmail.com
Mobile: +923139243550

OBJECTIVE

I am a 24 years old Software Engineer who loves to play with different technologies. I am looking forward for a promising technical job where I will be subjected to new developmental areas with friendly environment for learning and emerging of my own personality with professional and in time work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Decklaration Jun 2020 - present	MERN Stack Engineer Working for NY based design Agency. My main roles include developing Web Applications, Backend and Hybrid Mobile Applications.	Currently Remote
<u>Linknbit</u> Jan 2019 – May 2020	Software Engineer Working for Software Development and IT Solutions Agency. My main roles include developing Web Applications and Hybrid Mobile Applications.	Islamabad Pakistan

KYLA APP

It is a Mobile App to know your laws
 Recommended actions
 Contact lawyer with location and details
 Paid and Unpaid Feature
 Global Aviation System
 For Central African Republic
 Node JS, Express, MongoDB, Node mailer, Geolocation, Security for XSS and NOSQL Injection
 I am worked on parts of backend Node JS, Express,

Dynasty Unleashed Models

- Modeling agency App for Fashion designers and marketers
- Users can register, create profile, add people and hire models at will

Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native & part of Deployment to Firebase & Google Play

Sequelize CLI, PassportJS &

Azure SQL, Swagger

Developed the backend in

Dokkani.co

- Ecommerce Mobile App.
- User can register, select products, add products to cart.
- User add products to wish list and checkout.
- Project was abandoned on last stage due to funds not provided and outsourced to someone else.

React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Node JS, Rest API, Word Press API, Woo Commerce API, Native Base

My Version

Yogurt App

 Step-by-step guide to home crafted authentic Yogurt and Kefir. Take the directions on your phone. Make Yogurt and Kefir at home and communicate. Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native, Expo, Native Base

SmartsAid

NGO App for refuges

React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Firebase, Rest API, React Native Elements

2018 - FYP

Currency Recognition & Conversion

 Developed an app where users can scan currency note and it will tell which currency it is and how much is it and show the exchange rate in USD. Android, Java, Open CV, Rest API, MATLAB

2014 - 2018

Content Management Systems

Java, C#, MSSQL

Gym - Point of Sale

PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL

2010

RuneScape RPG

 Created bot script for the game called RuneScape. The bot played the game for you. Java

Portfolio Projects

DevCamper API

- Bootcamps API
- One can register as a User or Publisher and login also.
- Publisher can create Bootcamps.
- Admin and Publisher can add courses and perform various CRUD operations.
- Users can comment on Bootcamps and update their profile, add picture, and reset password.

HTML, NodeJS, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node mailer, Security for XSS and NOSQL Injection

DevConnector

- Social Media for developers where users register.
- Create profile, create posts, add comments and like and unlike them.

React, Redux, CSS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, NodeJS, Heroku

SmartBrain

- Smart Brain an app with face Recognition.
- Users can register, login and submit images via URL.
- The AI recognizes the face in the picture and draw a border around.
- It works only for one face in the image.

React, Redux, CSS, PostgreSQL, Knex, Express, Nodejs, Heroku, Netlify

The Color App

React, JSS, Material UI,

- A cross between flatuicolors and materialuicolors.
- Users can copy colors from palettes and create new color palettes, can also make colors lighter and darker by using the slider.
- When creating palettes one can also drag colors around and sort them however they like.

EDUCATION

Internet of things and Al Specialist Course

PIAIC, Islamabad (2019 - present)

BS in Software Engineering, cgpa 2.78

Institute of Managements Sciences, Peshawar (2014 – 2018)

F.Sc - Pre-Engineering, grade B

ICMS College System Peshawar (2012 – 2014)

10 Matric, grade A

Racines School System, Peshawar (2010 - 2012)

SPECIALITY AND KNOWLEDGE

Specialities

Mobile/Hybrid App Developer Web Developer

Social Links









Knowledge

React/React-Native, Redux, Expo JS, Node JS, Express Mongoose, Sequelize Firebase, Mongo DB HTML, CSS, JSS, Bootstrap Git, Heroku, Netlify Rest, GraphQL, MVC Rust

Word press, Android Studio, Adobe PS

LANGUAGES AND HOBBIES

Languages

English Urdu Pashto

Hobbies

Programming, Music, Movies, Video Games, Reading, Hiking, Bodybuilding,